Neslihan BABAARSLAN

Data Scientist

Turkey

in linkedin.com/in/neslihan-babaarslan/

+90 554 880 03 72

https://github.com/NeslihanBabaarslan

https://www.kaggle.com/neslihanbabaarslan



PROFILE

3 years of experience as a Data Scientist with Modelling Regression, Classification, Clustering and creating, evaluating and managing data frames using large data framework. 5 years professional career in Data Analysis with MS Excel, Statistical Modeling, Predictive Modelling, Exploratory Data Analysis, Data Manipulation, Data Visualization.

Academic research on Healthcare Datasets for the last 2 years especially with Deep Learning, Machine Learning, Data Processing, SQL, AWS. Experience in performing Supervised, Unsupervised ML and **Deep Learning Algorithms** to train and test the big data sets. Also experience working on commonly used python libraries such as NumPy, Pandas, Seaborn, Matplotlib, Plotly, Scikit-Learn, Tensorflow. Experienced in working in Agile environment. Strong analytical, creative thinking, problem solving, self-driven, highly motivated and pleasant personality.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python

Seaborn

SciKit-Learn

TensorFlow

Keras

SQL / MS SQL

Tableau

• Agile/Jira

Statistics

• Git/Github

Machine Learning

• Data Visualization

 Exploratory Data **Analysis**

AWS

EC2-Sagemaker

 Streamlit-Deployment

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

10/2020 - present

Data Analyst & Data Scientist, EXIMMAN Manufacturing and eCommerce

- Analyzing and visualizing keywords and product profitability,
- Product sales performance analysis that defines, measures and maintains using product metrics and KPIs,
- Preparing feasibility and investment reports for product launch,
- Data-driven product development using statistical analytics,
- Predictive modelling to increase and optimize customer service experiences,
- Understanding customer behavior and profile with customer segment analysis,
- Presenting result report and insights using tableau,
- Modeling regression analysis for sales estimates for Amazon US, EU marketplace.

02/2011 - present

Labour Inspector, Data Analyst, The Ministry of Labor and Social Security

- Evaluating the effectiveness of workplace inspectors by data-based analysis of annual inspection reports.
- Collecting data from workplaces, **creating a Healthcare dataframe**, analyzing using many methods and reporting in order to improve working condition.
- Developing and interpreting a statistical model (regression, classification, etc.) on the created healthcare dataframe.
- Providing insights into reasons for failure and success from exploratory data analysis
- · Presenting result report and insights using tableau,
- Working as a **team leader 3** years during the tenure

04/2019 – 04/2021 Turkey **Volunteer Experience,** *CoCoDer*

- Workshop event with children on April 23 National Sovereignty Children's Day
- Participation in activities to end child labor.
- Supporting activities to raise awareness of children's rights

EDUCATION

02/2018 – present Turkey	PhD - Chemical Engineering, <i>Ankara University</i> Thesis: IoT based control of nano CaCO3 synthesis using machine learning and deep learning algorithms.
08/2010 – 07/2013 Turkey	Master - Chemical Engineering, Ankara University Thesis: Accidental risk assessment in atmospheric distillation column in oil refinery
08/2004 – 06/2009 Turkey	Bachelor's - Chemical Engineering, Ankara University

PROJECTS

Churn Prediction for Bank Customer, *Tensorflow, Keras (ANN)*

A model that reflects whether a bank's customers leave the bank (close their accounts) or remain customers.

Cancer Classification, *Tensorflow, Keras (ANN)* □

Clothes Classification, *Tensorflow, Keras (CNN)* □

Malaria Data Classification, Tensorflow, Keras (CNN) ☑

Cat-Dog Classification, *Tensorflow, Keras (CNN)* □

The Dogs vs. Cats dataset is a common computer vision dataset in which pictures are classified as either including a dog or a cat.

Cancer Prediction, K-Nearest Neighbors-Pipeline □

Heart-Stroke Prediction, Logistic Regression, KNN Classifier, Yellowbrick □

With LogisticRegression, I created a model that can predict whether a patient is likely to get a stroke based on features like gender, age, various diseases, and smoking status.

Whether Prediction,

AdaBoosting, Gradientboosting, XGBoostig, Decision Tree, Logistic Regression, SVM, KNN ☐ Prediction model for whether a particular internet user clicks on an Ad on a company's website.

Slump Flow Modeling, *Linear, Lasso, Ridge, ElasticNet Regression* ☑ Modeling slump flow of concrete using Advanced Regression Parameters.

AutoScout Car Price Prediction Model, *Linear, Ridge, Lasso Regression* □

An original dataset taken directly from the given web page was used. With Dataset, a Machine Learning model was developed to predict the price of cars based on their given characteristics. You can find more details in the notebook for this project, where I tried to reach the most precise result with the least number of features.

Tree types prediction, SVC,Decision Tree, XGBoost, Random Forest ☑

Customer segmentation, *Random Forest, PCA* □

Car Pricing Model,

Random Forest Regression, AdaBoosting, GradientBoosting, XGBoosting Regressor ☑

Diabetes Analysis and Modeling, SVM □

AutoScout Price Prediction Deployment, *Xgboost, Streamlit,Sklearn, AWS* ☑

The Relationship Between Gender and Policing Project, Pandas- Matplotlib- Seaborn ☑

Customer Analysis, EDA, *Pandas- Matplotlib-Seaborn* ☑ Exploratory Data Analysis & Viz. on Customer dataset.

Bike Demand Project, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn

Customer Retention Analysis, MS Sql Server □

Nintendo Switch Company Sales Analysis, Tableau ☑

Covid-19 Tracking, Designed a Tableau Dashboard that focuses on cumulative and new cases/deaths globally for first quarter of 2022. -Tableau ☑

Exploratory Data Anlaysis with Autoscout, *Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn* ☑ Car price estimation consists of 3 steps of EDA Project: Data cleaning, Handling Missing Values, Handling outliers

Insurance Charges Prediction Model Deployment, *Linear Regressor(Lasso, Ridge), Random Forest Regressor, AdaBoosting, XGBoosting Regressor; Deployment-Streamlit*

Insurance charges estimation model according to people's age, bmi, smoking, etc.

CERTIFICATES

- Machine Learning with Python Clarusway ☑
- Data Visualization with Tableau Clarusway ☑
- Statistics Clarusway 🛮
- Data Analysis with Python IBM ☑
- Databases and SQL for Data Science with Python (HONORS) IBM $\ \square$
- Data Visualization with Python -Clarusway \square
- Deep Learning -Clarusway

PUBLICATIONS

30/12/2020	Data Sources Used For Risk Analysis in Industrial Facilities and a Sample Case Study,, Eskişehir Osmangazi Üniversitesi Mühendislik ve Mimarlık Fakültesi Dergisi. ☑
13/04/2014	Accidental Risk Assessment on Atmospheric Distillation Column in Oil Refinery,, Chemical Engineering Transactions